A Guide to the Trilateral Commission (North America) records FA420
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Task Force Reports/Projects, 1973-2001; 2; 44.99 Cubic Feet 115 letter document boxes and 1 record storage box
  - Report #46: Engaging Russia, 1995
    - Russia Project - Braithwaite (Box 197, Folder 2071)
    - Russia Project - Braithwaite - First Draft (with comments) (Box 197, Folder 2072)
    - Russia Project - Braithwaite - Second Draft (Box 197, Folder 2073)
    - Russia Project - Braithwaite - Third Draft, 1995 February 20 (Box 197, Folder 2074)
    - Russia Project - Blackwill - First Draft (Box 197, Folder 2075)
    - Russia Project - Blackwill - Second Draft (Box 197, Folder 2076)
    - Russia Project - Tanaka - First and Second Drafts (Box 197, Folder 2077)
    - Russia Project - Introductory Note (Box 197, Folder 2078)
    - Russia Project - Front Matter (Box 197, Folder 2079)
    - Russia Project - Braithwaite Pieces (Box 197, Folder 2080)
    - Russia Project - Blackwill Pieces (Box 197, Folder 2081)
    - Russia Project - Japan Pieces (Box 197, Folder 2082)
  - Report #47: Revitalizing Trilateral Democracies (Draft), 1995
    - Democracies Project - Report, 2 copies (Box 198, Folder 2083)
    - Democracies Project - Correspondence, 1995 January-June (Box 198, Folder 2084)
    - Democracies Project - Correspondence, 1995 July-December (Box 198, Folder 2085)
    - Democracies Project - Translation - French and German (Box 198, Folder 2086)
    - Democracies Project - Outlines, Drafts (Box 198, Folder 2087)
    - Democracies Project - Putnam Chapters (Box 198, Folder 2088)
    - Democracies Project - Casanova Chapter (Box 198, Folder 2089)
    - Democracies Project - Sato Chapter (Box 198, Folder 2090)
    - Democracies Project - Putnam Papers (Box 198, Folder 2091)
    - Democracies Project - Casanova Papers and European Background Pieces (Box 198, Folder 2092)
    - Democracies Project - Sato Papers and Japanese Background Pieces (Box 199, Folder 2093)
    - Democracies Project - Consultation Summaries, Notes, etc. (Box 199, Folder 2094)
    - Democracies Project - Copenhagen Draft (Box 199, Folder 2095)
    - Democracies Project - Copenhagen Discussion (Box 199, Folder 2096)
    - Democracies Project - Harvard Workshop Papers (Box 199, Folder 2097)
    - Democracies Project - Background Pieces (Box 199, Folder 2098)
    - Democracies Project - European Background Pieces (Box 199, Folder 2099)
  - Report #48: Maintaining Energy Security in a Global Context, 1996
    - Energy Project - Martin Presentations, Steeg (Box 200, Folder 2100)
    - Energy Project - Report Reviews (Box 200, Folder 2101)
    - Energy Project - Exxon Materials (Box 200, Folder 2102)
    - Energy Project - Steeg and Imari (Box 200, Folder 2103)
    - Energy Project - Correspondence, 1996 July-September (Box 200, Folder 2104)
    - Energy Project - Correspondence, 1996 April-June (Box 200, Folder 2105)
    - Energy Project - Correspondence, 1996 January-March (Box 201, Folder 2106)
    - Energy Project - Correspondence, 1995 October-December (Box 201, Folder 2107)
    - Energy Project - Correspondence, 1995 July-September (Box 201, Folder 2108)
    - Energy Project - Correspondence, 1995 April-June (Box 201, Folder 2109)
    - Energy Project - Pre Vancouver Editing (Box 201, Folder 2110)
    - Energy Project - Background (Box 202, Folder 2111)
    - Energy Project - Draft (for German Meeting), 1996 January (Box 202, Folder 2112)
    - Energy Project - Draft (before Plenary), 1995 September (Box 202, Folder 2113)
    - Energy Project - Martin Entries (Box 202, Folder 2114)
    - Energy Project - Consultations (Box 202, Folder 2115)
    - Energy Project - Correspondence and Memos (Bill Martin Office?) (Box 202, Folder 2116)
    - Energy Project - Memos (from Paris and Tokyo TC Offices) (Box 202, Folder 2117)
    - Energy Project - Imari Papers (Box 202, Folder 2118)
    - Energy Project - Martin Background Papers (Box 202, Folder 2119)
    - Energy Project - Steeg Papers (Box 203, Folder 2120)
    - Energy Project - Draft, 1996 April (Box 203, Folder 2120A)
  - Report #49: Globalization and Trilateral Labor Markets: Evidence and Implications, 1996
    - Globalization and Labor Project - Thygesen, etc. (Box 203, Folder 2121)
    - Globalization and Labor Project - Correspondence, Memos, 1995 (Box 203, Folder 2122)
    - Globalization and Labor Project - Correspondence, Memos, 1996 January-April (Box 203, Folder 2123)
    - Globalization and Labor Project - Post Vancouver - Correspondence (Box 203, Folder 2124)
    - Globalization and Labor Project - Post Vancouver - Intro Chapter (Box 203, Folder 2125)
    - Globalization and Labor Project - Post Vancouver - N.A. Chapter (Box 203, Folder 2126)
    - Globalization and Labor Project - Post Vancouver - Japan Chapter (Box 203, Folder 2127)
    - Globalization and Labor Project - Post Vancouver - Concluding Chapter (Box 203, Folder 2128)
    - Globalization and Labor Project - Post Vancouver - Europe Chapter (Box 203, Folder 2129)
    - Globalization and Labor Project - Post Vancouver - Front and Back Matter (Box 203, Folder 2130)
    - Globalization and Labor Project - Draft (April 1996) - Heck Editing, 1996 April (Box 203, Folder 2130A)
    - Globalization and Labor Project - Vancouver Draft - Front Matter (Box 203, Folder 2131)
    - Globalization and Labor Project - Vancouver Draft - Chapter I and Intro (Box 204, Folder 2132)
    - Globalization and Labor Project - Vancouver Draft - Chapter II (Box 204, Folder 2133)
    - Globalization and Labor Project - Vancouver Draft - Chapter III (Box 204, Folder 2134)
    - Globalization and Labor Project - Vancouver Draft - Chapter IV (Box 204, Folder 2135)
    - Globalization and Labor Project - Vancouver Draft - Chapter V (Box 204, Folder 2136)
    - Globalization and Labor Project - Vancouver Draft - Back Matter (Box 204, Folder 2137)
    - Globalization and Labor Project - Background Materials (Box 204, Folder 2138)
  - Report #50: Managing the International System Over the Next Ten Years: Three Essays, 1997
    - Managing the International System Project - Emmott Essay (Box 204, Folder 2139)
    - Managing the International System Project - Watanabe Essay (Box 204, Folder 2140)
    - Managing the International System Project - Wolfowitz Essay (Box 204, Folder 2141)
    - Managing the International System Project - Correspondence (Box 204, Folder 2142)
    - Managing the International System Project - Preliminary Background (Box 205, Folder 2143)
    - Managing the International System Project - Draft - Tokyo Meeting (Box 205, Folder 2144)
    - Managing the International System Project - Front Matter (Box 205, Folder 2145)
  - Report #51: Community-Building With Pacific Asia, 1997
    - Pacific Asia Project - 3 (Box 205, Folder 2146)
    - Pacific Asia Project - 2 (Box 205, Folder 2147)
    - Pacific Asia Project - 1 (Box 205, Folder 2148)
    - Pacific Asia Project - Post Tokyo - Front Matter (Box 205, Folder 2149)
    - Pacific Asia Project - Post Tokyo - Chapter 1 (Box 205, Folder 2150)
    - Pacific Asia Project - Post Tokyo - Chapter 2 (Box 205, Folder 2151)
    - Pacific Asia Project - Post Tokyo - Chapter 3 (Box 205, Folder 2152)
    - Pacific Asia Project - Post Tokyo - Chapter 4 (Box 205, Folder 2153)
    - Pacific Asia Project - Post Tokyo - Chapter 4 (Box 205, Folder 2154)
    - Pacific Asia Project - Post Tokyo - Chapter 5 (Box 205, Folder 2155)
    - Pacific Asia Project - Post Tokyo - Chapter 6 (Box 205, Folder 2156)
    - Pacific Asia Project - Post Tokyo - Chapter 7 (Box 205, Folder 2157)
    - Pacific Asia Project - Post Tokyo - Chapter 8 (Box 205, Folder 2158)
    - Pacific Asia Project - Post Tokyo - Maps (Box 205, Folder 2159)
    - Pacific Asia Project - Post Tokyo - Chapter 9 (Box 205, Folder 2160)
    - Pacific Asia Project - Post Tokyo - Chapter 10 (Box 205, Folder 2161)
    - Pacific Asia Project - Post Tokyo - Chapter 11 (Box 205, Folder 2162)
    - Pacific Asia Project - Post Tokyo - Appendix (Box 206, Folder 2163)
    - Pacific Asia Project - Post Tokyo - Appendix (Original), 1997 September 22 (Box 206, Folder 2164)
    - Pacific Asia Project - Post Tokyo - Appendix (Original), 1997 October 12 (Box 206, Folder 2165)
    - Pacific Asia Project - Post Tokyo - List of Readings (Box 206, Folder 2166)
    - Pacific Asia Project - Pre Tokyo - Chapter 1 (Box 206, Folder 2167)
    - Pacific Asia Project - Pre Tokyo - Chapter 2 (Box 206, Folder 2168)
    - Pacific Asia Project - Pre Tokyo - Chapter 3 (Box 206, Folder 2169)
    - Pacific Asia Project - Pre Tokyo - Chapter 4 (Box 206, Folder 2170)
    - Pacific Asia Project - Pre Tokyo - Chapter 5 (Box 206, Folder 2171)
    - Pacific Asia Project - Pre Tokyo - Chapter 6 (Box 206, Folder 2172)
    - Pacific Asia Project - Pre Tokyo - Chapter 7 (Box 206, Folder 2173)
    - Pacific Asia Project - Pre Tokyo - Chapter 8 (Box 206, Folder 2174)
    - Pacific Asia Project - Pre Tokyo - Chapter 9 (Box 206, Folder 2175)
    - Pacific Asia Project - Pre Tokyo - Chapter 10 (Box 206, Folder 2176)
    - Pacific Asia Project - Pre Tokyo - Chapter 11 (Box 206, Folder 2177)
    - Pacific Asia Project - Pre Tokyo - Front Matter (Box 206, Folder 2178)
    - Pacific Asia Project - Consultations, Ottawa, 1997 February (Box 206, Folder 2179)
    - Pacific Asia Project - Consultations, Washington/New York, 1997 January-February (Box 206, Folder 2179A)
    - Pacific Asia Project - Draft, 1997 March (Box 206, Folder 2180)
    - Pacific Asia Project - Early Outlines, Draft Elements (Box 207, Folder 2181)
    - Pacific Asia Project - Background Materials (Box 207, Folder 2182)
    - Pacific Asia Project - Correspondence with Charles Morrison (Box 207, Folder 2183)
    - Pacific Asia Project - Other Correspondence (Box 207, Folder 2184)
  - Report #52: Advancing Common Purposes in the Broad Middle East, 1998
    - Plenary Meeting, Berlin - Middle East Excerpts (Box 208, Folder 2185)
    - Plenary Meeting, Berlin - Middle East Excerpts (Box 208, Folder 2186)
    - Plenary Meeting, Berlin - Substantive Background Papers (Box 208, Folder 2187)
    - Plenary Meeting, Berlin - Pelletreau (Box 208, Folder 2188)
    - Plenary Meeting, Berlin - Schlagintweit (Box 208, Folder 2188A)
    - Plenary Meeting, Berlin - Nogami (Box 208, Folder 2188B)
    - Plenary Meeting, Berlin - Moisi (Box 208, Folder 2189)
    - Plenary Meeting, Berlin - Berlin Draft (Box 208, Folder 2190)
  - Task Force Reports - Published, 1973-2001; 1 copy unless otherwise noted
    - 1: Towards a Renovated World Monetary System, 1973 (Box 209, Folder 2191)
    - 2: The Crisis of International Cooperation, 1974 (Box 209, Folder 2192)
    - 3: A Turning Point in North-South Economic Relations, 1974 (Box 209, Folder 2193)
    - 4: Directions for World Trade in the Nineteen-Seventies, 1974 (Box 209, Folder 2194)
    - 5: Energy: The Imperative for a Trilateral Approach, 1974 (Box 209, Folder 2195)
    - 6: Energy: A Strategy for International Action, 1974 (Box 209, Folder 2196)
    - 7: OPEC, the Trilateral World, and the Developing Countries: New Arrangements for Cooperation, 1976-1980, 1975 (Box 209, Folder 2197)
    - 1-7 Combined Volume (Box 209, Folder 2198)
    - 8: The Crisis of Democracy, 1975; 2 copies (Box 209, Folder 2199)
    - 9-14 Combined Volume (Box 209, Folder 2200)
    - 10: Seeking a New Accommodation in World Commodity Markets, 1976 (Box 209, Folder 2201)
    - 11: The Reform of International Institutions, 1976 (Box 209, Folder 2202)
    - 12: The Problem of International Consultations, 1976 (Box 209, Folder 2203)
    - 13: Collaboration with Communist Countries in Managing Global Problems: An Examination of the Options, 1977 (Box 209, Folder 2204)
    - 14: Towards a Renovated International System, 1977 (Box 209, Folder 2205)
    - 15-19 Combined Volume (Box 209, Folder 2206)
    - 15: An Overview of East-West Relations, 1978 (Box 209, Folder 2207)
    - 16: Reducing Malnutrition in Developing Countries: Increasing Rice Production in South and Southeast Asia, 1978 (Box 209, Folder 2208)
    - 17: Energy: Managing the Transition, 1978 (Box 209, Folder 2209)
    - 18: Collective Bargaining and Employee Participation in Western Europe, North America and Japan, 1979 (Box 209, Folder 2210)
    - 19: Industrial Policy and the International Economy, 1979 (Box 209, Folder 2211)
    - 21: Trade in Manufactured Products with Developing Countries: Reinforcing North-South Partnership, 1981; 2 copies (Box 209, Folder 2212)
    - 22: The Middle East and the Trilateral Countries, 1981; 2 copies (Box 209, Folder 2213)
    - 23: The Trilateral Countries in the International Economy of the 1980s, 1982; 2 copies (Box 209, Folder 2214)
    - 24: East-West Trade at a Crossroads: Economic Relations with the Soviet Union and Eastern Europe, 1982; 2 copies (Box 209, Folder 2215)
    - 25: Sharing International Responsibilities Among the Trilateral Countries, 1982; 2 copies (Box 209, Folder 2216)
    - 28: Democracy Must Work: A Trilateral Agenda for the Decade, 1984; 2 copies (Box 209, Folder 2217)
    - 29: Agricultural Policy & Trade: Adjusting Domestic Programs in an International Framework, 1985; 2 copies (Box 209, Folder 2218)
    - 30: East Asian Security & The Trilateral Countries, 1985; 2 copies (Box 209, Folder 2219)
    - 31: Prospects for East-West Relations, 1986; 2 copies (Box 209, Folder 2220)
    - 32: Conditions for Partnership in International Economic Management, 1986; 2 copies (Box 209, Folder 2221)
    - 33: Restoring Growth in the Debt-Laden Third World, 1987; 2 copies (Box 209, Folder 2222)
    - 34: Science and Technology in Trilateral Relations: Competition and Cooperation (Draft), 1987 March; 2 copies (Box 209, Folder 2223)
    - 35: East Asia in Transition: Challenges for the Trilateral Countries, 1988; 2 copies (Box 209, Folder 2224)
    - 36: East-West Relations, 1989; 2 copies (Box 209, Folder 2225)
    - 37: International Financial Integration: The Policy Challenges, 1989 (Box 209, Folder 2226)
    - 38: The Israeli-Palestinian Issue, 1990 (Box 209, Folder 2227)
    - 39: Latin America at a Crossroads: The Challenge to the Trilateral Countries, 1990 (Box 209, Folder 2228)
    - 40: Beyond Interdependence: The Meshing of the World's Economy and the Earth's Ecology, 1991; 2 copies (Box 209, Folder 2229)
    - 41: Global Cooperation After the Cold War: A Reassessment of Trilateralism, 1991; 2 copies (Box 209, Folder 2230)
    - 42: Regionalism in a Converging World, 1992 (Box 209, Folder 2231)
    - 43: Keeping the Peace in the Post-Cold War Era: Strengthening Multilateral Peacekeeping, 1993; 2 copies (Box 209, Folder 2232)
    - 44: International Migration Challenges in a New Era, 1993; 2 copies (Box 209, Folder 2233)
    - 45: An Emerging China in a World of Interdependence, 1994; 2 copies (Box 209, Folder 2234)
    - 46: Engaging Russia, 1995; 2 copies (Box 209, Folder 2235)
    - 47: Revitalizing Trilateral Democracies (Draft), 1995 (Box 209, Folder 2236)
    - 48: Maintaining Energy Security in a Global Context, 1996; 2 copies (Box 209, Folder 2237)
    - 49: Globalization and Trilateral Labor Markets: Evidence and Implications, 1996 (Box 209, Folder 2238)
    - 50: Managing the International System Over the Next Ten Years: Three Essays, 1997; 2 copies (Box 209, Folder 2239)
    - 51: Community-Building With Pacific Asia (2 copies), 1997 (Box 209, Folder 2240)
    - 53: 21st Century Strategies of the Trilateral Countries: In Concert or Conflict?, 1999 (Box 209, Folder 2241)
    - 54: The New Central Asia: In Search of Stability, 2000; 2 copies (Box 209, Folder 2242)
    - 55: East Asia and The International System, 2001; 2 copies (Box 209, Folder 2243)
    - Task Force Reports Brochure Insert (Reports 1-30) (Box 209, Folder 2244)
    - Working Group Papers, 1991-1992; 2 copies (Box 209, Folder 2245)
- Publications, 1973-2000; 3; 14.02 Cubic Feet 30 letter document boxes and 2 record storage boxes
  The Publications series contains documentation of the Commission's principal publication Trialogue, as well as the Commission's Annual Reports, 1974-1991, and a limited selection of publication distribution files.
  Trialogue serves as the Commission's bulletin or newsletter including documentation of the Annual Meeting, other reports, speeches, and relevant policy discussions. Trialogue began as a mimeographed bulletin circulated to members and friends. It became a printed affair in 1975. With Francois Sauzey as its editor it grew to a substantial magazine with one issue each year covering the annual meeting of the Commission and other issues each covering specific topics. But its subscriber base was not large enough to sustain an expanded publication schedule. In mid-1984, after Sauzey left the staff, Trialogue shifted to producing only one issue each year covering the annual plenary meeting. There were two special issues in the 1990s – a compilation of the Working Group papers in 1992, and the Commission's 25th Anniversary in 1998 (with Sauzey returning as its editor).
  The Trialogue records are loosely arranged by Issue Number, 1-54 (1973-2000).
  Some issues of Trialogue have related files, correspondence and work product within the collection. Many issues are represented only by a copy of the final publication. Final publications are available in Boxes 220-223.
  Archival material related to Issue 4 is in Box 340 only. No final publication copy of Issue 4 is available.
  Francois Sauzey Files – Sauzey was a member of the Commission's New York staff from mid-1976 through mid-1984. His primary responsibility was to act as editor of Trialogue. Sauzey also handled much of the Commission's public relations. In addition to Sauzey's Trialogue and public relations records, his files also contain meeting records and correspondence from his time with the Commission.
  Trilateral Commission - Trialogue Issues
  T1. Trialogue: A Bulletin Of North American-European-Japanese Affairs: Oct. 1973. The Trilateral Commission (© 1973). Ed: Michael J. Sodaro. 6pp. Related Archival Material: Box 210, 336.
  T2. Trialogue: A Bulletin Of North American-European-Japanese Affairs: Nov 1973. (Includes "Statement Of Purposes" Of The Trilateral Commission). The Trilateral Commission (© 1973). Ed: Michael J. Sodaro. Related Archival Material: Box 210, 220.
  T3. Trialogue: A Bulletin Of North American-European-Japanese Affairs: Dec. 1973 - Jan. 1974. The Trilateral Commission (© 1974). Ed: Michael J. Sodaro. Includes contribution by: Robert R. Bowie. 6pp. Related Archival Material: Box 210, 220.
  T4. Trialogue: A Bulletin Of North American-European-Japanese Affairs: Feb-Mar. 1974. The Trilateral Commission (© 1974). Ed: Michael J. Sodaro. 6pp. Related Archival Material: Box 340.
  T5. Trialogue: A Bulletin Of North American-European-Japanese Affairs: May-July 1974. The Trilateral Commission (© 1974). Ed: Charles B. Heck. Contributions by: Kazushige Hirasawa and Harold Brown. 18pp. Related Archival Material: Box 210, 220.
  T6. Commission Recommends Cooperation With Oil-Exporters, Proposes New Aid Agency, Consults With Ford And Kissinger. The Trilateral Commission (© 1975). Ed: Charles B. Heck. Contributions by: Nobuhiko Ushiba, Paul Delouvrier, George W. Ball and Andrew Shonfield. 16pp. Related Archival Material: Box 210, 220.
  T7. Trilateral Leaders Discuss Global Redistribution Of Power And Problems Of Trilateral Community, Japan, May 1975. The Trilateral Commission (© 1975). Ed: Charles B. Heck. Contributions by: Takeshi Watanabe, Saburo Okita, Ralf Dahrendorf and Zbigniew Brzezinski. 16pp. Related Archival Material: Box 210, 220.
  T8. Is Reform An Illusion? A Trilateral Perspective On International Relations. The Trilateral Commission (© 1975). Ed: Charles B. Heck. Contributions by: Christopher J. Makins and Charles B. Heck. 8pp. Related Archival Material: Box 210, 220.
  T9. Economic Cooperation And Resource Management. The Trilateral Commission (© 1976). Ed: Charles B. Heck. Contributions by: Guido Carli, Claude Cheysson and Kinhide Mushakoji. 15pp. Related Archival Material: Box 210, 220.
  T10. Looking Back.....And Forward. The Trilateral Commission (© 1976). Ed: Charles B. Heck. Contributions by: Richard N. Cooper, Richard N. Gardner, Philip H. Tresize, John C. Campbell, Samuel P. Huntington, John H. Perkins, P. Nyboe Andersen, Marina v.N. Whitman, Peter Dobell and Takeshi Watanabe. 12pp. Related Archival Material: Box 210, 220.
  T11. Improper Corporate Payoffs Termed A "Cancer" Which Weakens Firms, Subverts Markets And Threatens Democratic Values, May 1976 Ottawa Meeting. The Trilateral Commission (© 1976). Ed: Charles B. Heck. Contributions by: Pierre Trudeau, Lloyd N. Cutler and Zbigniew Brzezinski. 16pp. Related Archival Material: Box 210, 220.
  T12. The Governability Debate Continued. The Trilateral Commission (© 1976). Ed: Charles B. Heck. Contributions by: Peter Jenkins, Walter Dean Burnham, Yonosuke Nagai, and Umberto Colombo. 11pp. Related Archival Material: Box 220.
  T13. Trade Issues And Macroeconomic Coordination Highlight Trilateral Tokyo Meeting, January 1977. The Trilateral Commission (© 1977). Ed: François Sauzey. Contributions by: Marina v.N. Whitman, Thierry de Montbrial, Saburo Okita, Iichiro Hatoyama and Kiichi Miyazawa. 19pp. Related Archival Material: Box 210, 220, 343.
  T14. Managing Global Relations: Avenues For Trilateral-Communist Collaboration. The Trilateral Commission (© 1977). Ed: François Sauzey. Contributions by: Fred Sanderson, Fuji Kamiya, Yevgeniy Rusakov, John Pinder and Gerald Parsky. 20pp. Related Archival Material: Box 210, 220, 356.
  T15. Trilateral Meeting In Bonn Discusses East-West Relations And Strategies To Increase Food Production In LDCs And Non-Proliferation Policies. The Trilateral Commission (© 1977). Ed: François Sauzey. Contributions by: Gerard C. Smith, Kinya Niizeki, André Giraud, Zbigniew Brzezinski and Bunroku Yoshino. Related Archival Material: Box 210, 220, 223, 356.
  T16. The London Summit Revisited. The Trilateral Commission (© 1978). Ed: François Sauzey. Contributions by: Henry Owen, Meinhard Miegel, Bunroku Yoshino and Fabio Basagni. 12pp. Related Archival Material: Box 220.
  T17. Doubling Rice Production In Asia. The Trilateral Commission (© 1978). Ed: François Sauzey. Contributions by: James P. Grant, The Guinness Peat Group, M. Yudelman, Francis Wells and Kenzo Henmi. 16pp. Related Archival Material: Box 210, 220.
  T18. Energy, Industrial Relations and Trilateral Economic problems: Major Issues At Trilateral Meeting in Washington, D.C., June 1978. The Trilateral Commission (© 1978). Ed: François Sauzey. Contributions by: Harold Brown, Klaus von Dohnanyi, W. Michael Blumenthal, Nobuhiko Ushiba, Etienne Davignon and Kiichi Miyazawa. 19pp. Related Archival Material: Box 220.
  T19. The Politics Of Human Rights. The Trilateral Commission (© 1978). Ed: François Sauzey. Contributions by: Claude Cheysson, Henry A. Kissinger, Andrei Sakharov, Ali A. Mazrui, Ribot Hatano, Horst Ehmke, Tom Farer, Romesh Thapar, Mihajlo Mihajlov, Jean-Marie Benoist and Gordon Fairweather. 36pp. Related Archival Material: Box 210, 211, 212, 220.
  T20. 10th Trilateral Meeting In Tokyo, April 1979. The Trilateral Commission (© 1979). Ed: François Sauzey. Contributions by: Masayoshi Ohira, Otto Graf Lambsdorff, Kiichi Miyazawa, Yasuo Takeyama, Walter M. Heller, Endymion Wilkinson, Yusuke Kashiwagi, Michel Oksenberg and Kiichi Saeki. 24pp. Related Archival Material: Box 212, 220.
  T21. Security In The 1980s. The Trilateral Commission (© 1979). Ed: François Sauzey. Contributions by: Harold Brown, Alexander Haig, François de Rose, Karl Kaiser, Takuya Kubo and Toru Yano. 28pp. Related Archival Material: Box 210, 213, 220, 234.